# **DAVIS MARTIN**

#### SUMMARY

Junior Full Stack Developer with 9 years of experience in Java and JavaScript and their frameworks -Angular, Vue, React, Python. Developed over 50 websites from scratch at Siteground, improved security by 25%, and attracted 500K new customers to SportsBet after developing & implementing new datadriven features. Seeking opportunity to leverage front-end skills and increase customer engagement at Hopper.

### **SKILLS**

HTML · CSS · JavaScript · React ·

React Native · Next.js · Vue.js ·

Typescript · Tailwind CSS · Node.js ·

Express.js · MongoDB · MySQL ·

PostgreSQL · Flutter · Python · C# ·

C++ · Java · Figma · Photoshop · PHP ·

Laravel · Codelgniter · WordPress ·

BlockChain · Web Development ·

Website Design

### **LANGUAGES**

English	Fluent
Espanol	Conversational
Hindi	Fluent
French	Fluent
Detush	Fluent

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**



What are you most proud of?

> Why are you proud of this achievement?

# Full Stack Developer

♣ Phone @ jamesmartinok@outlook.com Los Angeles US

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Junior Full Stack Developer

Present

**SportsBet** 

New York US

SportsBet is a world-famous website where people can place bets on matches, competitions, and athletes in over 40 sports online and through a mobile app

- Led a team of 3 developers on launch of mobile app upgrade, increased customer engagement by 30% and earned an additional \$150K in the first year
- Developed over 20 new data-driven features in Java (EJB2, Spring, Hibernate, Swing), which attracted over 500K new customers in 2020
- Developed several data automation systems saving over \$250K annually
- Collaborated with the UX designers to create a new look and feel for the website, implemented changes with jQuery library extensions, Ajax & CSS, increasing the average time users spend on the website by 20 minutes

### Front End Developer

04/2015 - 12/2018

ValueTech

Milan, Italy

Help organizations to generate value with software. Have a holistic, non-dogmatic, value-based approach to software development. To generate value with software, developers need exquisite technology, an agile mindset and a great development team.

- Solid understanding of user experience design principles and best practices
- Knowledge of popular content management systems such as WordPress and
- Experience with version control systems such as Git and Subversion
- Proficient in crossbrowser compatibility issues and web standards
- Expertise in creating and modifying style sheets, layouts, and graphics for web applications and websites
- Proven success in developing frontend apps using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and AJAX

# Junior Full Stack Developer

12/2018 - 12/2022

# SiteGround

New York, United States

SiteGround is a company that provides website solutions for small-business owners at affordable prices with a portfolio featuring over 700 webpages

- Increased the performance of 20 customer-facing webpages and increased revenue by 40%
- Designed and developed front-end GUI for over 20 applications using JSP, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, and Ajax
- Identified error in back-end code and provided solution that increased customer satisfaction rating to 93% and resulted in \$70K in earnings the following guarter

### **EDUCATION**

### B.S. in Computer Science

07/2009 - 03/2013

### New York Institute of Technology

### **STRENGTHS**



#### Eager to learn new skills

Always looking to grow, stay up-to-date on latest tech trends and coding languages



### Time management

Prioritize tasks and organize workflow to maximize productivity without sacrificing quality

# **STRENGTHS**



## Collaborative

Work well on a team and collaborate with developers on app development and launch

Powered by CO Enhancu